introducing incredible police is a man
that you just heard Dan speak oh he was
part of that initial class of 2010 into
the Cleveland International Hall of Fame
Alex majeski and as a journalist I can
say thank you for your efforts sir in
what you did for the Plain Dealer and
what you did for the people of Northeast
Ohio and Ohio in general that name in
that paper symbolized something and
still does to this day we're at a point
in time where journalism is an
interesting space to occupy and when you
look at people like this who made a
difference in our community and really
kind of hone the skills of journalists
in their charge and make people in
community better in the more form 13
years ago three months later I like to
offer my congratulations to this
evening's outstanding Assembly of
honorees it's an honor for me to be
asked to introduce in credo poopless the
honorary consul general of Republic of
Lithuania ingredient in my view is a gem
and the crown jewels of diplomacy
she is revered by the Athenians in the
United States in Lithuania in Rita as
president of the International
has accomplished much in her 30 years in
business development and company
representation between Baltic states
like Latvia and Estonia and the United
States IV international represents a
number of US companies in various
industry sectors while also representing
and opening doors for the first range of
Lithuanian companies in the u.s. in Rita
has secured establish contacts for a
development for various Baltic companies
as well as US companies in development
strong network across the first
commercial government interest she
organized the world with fellini an
economic conference in Chicago she is a
rare combination of successful
international business momentum and
ethnic community leader in credo serves
on various boards has been awarded the
order of brand new event on Tess
degraded by the Athenian government the
American nationalities movements Eagle
Award and international Rotary Club
International Service Award last year in
this mania on the occasion of the 20th
annual of the restoration of
independence and greed it was chosen one
of the 100 women of Athenian that all
the way Nia's worldwide are proud of and
many other recognitions she stowed upon
her community and the business
community's ingredients has been the
honor a general consul of the Republic
of Lithuania for the states of Ohio
Indiana Kentucky
22 years promoting friendly relations
between between yet the United States he
has established good relations with
steadiest state officials educational
institutions and US corporations she's
an active networker through various
organizations and developing contacts I
always wanted to emulate and great up
because I ste put the wanying flags
everywhere so I said to the Prime
Minister of Serbia a few years of a
question you know I watched what the
Lithuanian and others do I says but when
I want to fly in the Serbian flag over a
City Hall I have to do this my own
precious big way so the very next time
the Prime Minister came to Cleveland
he brought me his Serbian flag it was
just bait it was a desperate greta's
instrumental in connecting the Ohio
University's with Manian universities
and various exchange programs on the
state level a relationship between the
Department of Agriculture Ohio and the
Ministry of Agriculture with mania she
is a tireless organizer of trade
missions most successfully bringing all
events and providing access with this
plane and government officials to key
decision u.s. makers and people of
influence she's been involved over the
years and does the main cultural groups
and more Shima marches in parades her
business acumen has been her leadership
roles in the Rotary Club of Cleveland we
here
I've been proud of ingredients for many
years
[Laughter]
[Applause]
good evening opportunities early honored
in receiving this recognition and also
to be conducted by my colleague consul
of Serbia
Alex Magesty thank you so much he's
truly one of the pillars in this great
city of Cleveland for those lovely words
at this time I would also like to
commend Cleveland people calm for
organizing at the stablishing this
international policy and for their
dedication actually to always watch what
all these ethnic communities do and to
always document our work thank you so
much we believe that
[Applause]
at this time I would also like to thank
my parents actually it's called me the
love of their homeland between my
husband and my children who have been
great supporters to my activities
throughout the years you know it was
mentioned that 10 years ago with the
first installation class of the
Cleveland International House of Payne
it just seems like yesterday and I had
the honor that evening in 2010 to induct
Senator George Voinovich I'll never
forget George Voinovich he was such a
conscientious person of all of his
constituents he stood by all our
countries that at that time were
yearning that freedom would ring on
their shores and you know it was also
mentioned tonight that George Voinovich
had said if you are proud of your
heritage you are a great American you
know as I lived on this evening
I see Cleveland a truly beautiful
tapestry you all are the people that are
proud of your heritage and the workers
that make this land great that we call
America and events like this like this
evening banquet encourages all of us to
keep working
so much
[Applause]